Kristof G. Herrmann

kristof.herrmann@rwth-aachen.de · +49 151 2014 2005 · Cologne, Germany

Highly motivated mathematician and developer (IoT) with keen interest in complex problems. More than 2 years of experience in developing industrial software from shopfloor level to the cloud. Project management, requirements analysis, planning, testing and documentation.



"I want to further improve my project management skills, take on responsibility and be part of an innovative team that creates digital solutions with real added value."

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senseering GmbH

Full Stack Software Engineer - Cologne Developer of a decentralized data sharing platform in the spirit of GAIA-X. Technical consultant IoT solutions. since April 2020

• WZL der RWTH Aachen

Working Student - Aachen Developer of a decentralized data sharing platform in the spirit of GAIA-X with a focus on Data Science. April 2019 - April 2020

• PricewaterhouseCoopers GmbH

Intern Business Intelligence - Düsseldorf Development of a planning tool for the maintenance and repair of vehicles for a large German transport service provider.

October 2018 - Februar 2019

RWTH Aachen

Tutor for higher mathematics - Aachen October 2015 - September 2018

EDUCATION

• M.Sc. Mathematics Ø1.0

Focus on partial differential equations. Field of application: computer science. Rheinisch-Westfälische Technische Hochschule Aachen Autumn 2017 - Autumn 2019

• B.Sc. Mathematics Ø1.8

Field of application: Focus on measure theory. computer science. Rheinisch-Westfälische Technische Hochschule Aachen

Autumn 2014 - Autumn 2017

AWARDS

• Springorum-Denkmünze proRWTH - top 10% of each faculty 2020

SKILLS

• Programming languages & Databases

Nodejs, Vue, Python, MySQL, Mongodb, InfluxDB, Elasticsearch, Redis

Cloud & Technologies

S3/Azure Blob Storage, EC2, CodeBuild, CodePipeline, CDN, ECS, ELK, Azure IoT Hub, Grafana, Docker, Portainer, Node Red, Github Actions, DynamoDB, AWS Cognito, KeyCloak, Auth0, IOTA, Nginx, httpd

• Mathematics

Partial differential equations, measure theory, numerical analysis, financial mathematics

Languages

german, english

PROJECTS

• spaicer [spaicer.de]

Scalable adaptive production systems through AIbased resilience optimization - Project responsibility. IoT, machine learning, AI

• obsidian [Senseering/obsidian]

A Nodejs based immutability layer for (industrial) data Release pending Nodejs, IOTA

• MyDataEconomy [mydataeconomy.com]

Decentralized IoT data sharing platform for sovereign data exchange.

GAIA-X, Nodejs, Docker, IOTA, InfluxDB

• Duck [arzelaascoii.github.io/UAVDocs] Autonomous flying solar plane built from scratch. UAV, Ardupilot, ROS, Docusaurus







kgherr ArzelaAscoIi @Kristof.herrmann